<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vent Drop | an infosec blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Vent Drop | an infosec blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 16:34:16 +1100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Gachiloader pt2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/gachiloaderpt2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 16:34:16 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/gachiloaderpt2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;intro&#34;&gt;Intro&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re back. &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@rcgatenby/malware-roulette-1-gachiloader-pt-1-84cba7e7cd17&#34;&gt;When we left this sample in part one&lt;/a&gt;, we had:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Extracted files from the original .msi installer&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Dynamically analysed the obfuscated JavaScript file&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Spoofed anti-debugging call checks to drop the loader&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Got the loader to drop the final payload&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After spending some time statically and dynamically analysing this sample, I was able to uncover both the C2 and the malware variant. TLDR; as expected, the malware family was Rhadamanthys (an infostealer). This blog will focus mostly on the immense number of anti-debugging checks in the &amp;ldquo;final payload&amp;rdquo;, as touched on briefly in pt1. Hope you enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Malware Roulette #1 - GachiLoader pt. 1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/gachiloader/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 14:06:28 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/gachiloader/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;intro&#34;&gt;Intro&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I was randomly browsing AnyRun looking for something to poke at, when I came across &lt;a href=&#34;https://app.any.run/tasks/02b1a4fa-ed88-459a-b1fa-bc51a38aa188&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt;. The URL being scanned was hxxps://anysoft[.]click, which appeared to redirect to a file hosted on MediaFire. It&amp;rsquo;s unclear how a user might have landed at this site. AnyRun sandbox flagged some powershell commands as &amp;lsquo;Scarface Stealer&amp;rsquo;, which may or may not be accurate attribution.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/static/gachiloader/Image2.png&#34; alt=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;node-malware&#34;&gt;Node Malware&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In any case, the file to be downloaded from MediaFire was &lt;code&gt;Set-Up.rar&lt;/code&gt;. This .rar archive contains a single file, &lt;code&gt;Set-Up.msi&lt;/code&gt;, a Microsoft Installer file. When inspecting this .msi, we see embedded files, which we can extract using a tool such as &lt;code&gt;LessMsi&lt;/code&gt;. This contained the following four files:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DLL Sideloading - JRTools.dll</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/jriver/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 17:12:41 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/jriver/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Just a quick blog post to provide research for a &lt;a href=&#34;https://hijacklibs.net/&#34;&gt;HijackLibs&lt;/a&gt; submission. The software &lt;code&gt;J River Media Center&lt;/code&gt;, which can be downloaded from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jriver.com/download.html&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; contains an executable (&lt;code&gt;JRService.exe&lt;/code&gt;) that is vulnerable to DLL sideloading. DLL sideloading matters because it allows attackers to run malicious code under the cover of a trusted, digitally signed program, making the attack nearly invisible to many security tools that only scrutinize the &amp;ldquo;safe&amp;rdquo; executable.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;testing&#34;&gt;Testing&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;During testing, the file &lt;code&gt;MediaCenter350038-x64.exe&lt;/code&gt; was downloaded and used. This file has the following SHA256: &lt;code&gt;5ba63f08692ae6a7d70d0b9c7414d85928ae86e59d5e4aef59e6b5a98e2f1e09&lt;/code&gt;.&#xA;When this setup installer is run and the application is installed, files are created in the directory &lt;code&gt;C:\Program Files\J River\Media Center 35&lt;/code&gt;.&#xA;When the application is installed using this method, and the files &lt;code&gt;JRService.exe&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;JRTools.dll&lt;/code&gt; exist in those locations, the application will load this dll no matter where else these files are placed on disk.&#xA;During testing, the SHA256 hash of &lt;code&gt;JRService.exe&lt;/code&gt; was &lt;code&gt;73dc3291cbc89663ecec0c5169000cc0bf153dab7decefabd31fc12bae2fc548&lt;/code&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.virustotal.com/gui/file/73dc3291cbc89663ecec0c5169000cc0bf153dab7decefabd31fc12bae2fc548&#34;&gt;VT&lt;/a&gt; and the SHA256 hash of &lt;code&gt;JRTools.dll&lt;/code&gt; was &lt;code&gt;e422bf2cc1dec97c132edb7345f180dd0c6faccd34ad62a874fe6420a5da16a9&lt;/code&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.virustotal.com/gui/file/e422bf2cc1dec97c132edb7345f180dd0c6faccd34ad62a874fe6420a5da16a9&#34;&gt;VT&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FortiGate DFIR Notes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/forti/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 17:38:40 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/forti/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This blog post doesn&amp;rsquo;t contain any cutting edge exploitation or custom security tooling, but it contains some things that I didn&amp;rsquo;t know previously and know now, and my hope is that it helps someone else learn something new or helps someone secure something that wasn&amp;rsquo;t previously.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/static/forti/respect_the_research.png&#34; alt=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;bluf---for-those-short-on-time-or-home-to-a-cracked-attention-span&#34;&gt;BLUF - For those short on time or home to a cracked attention span&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a TL;DR of some of the learnings:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&#xA;&lt;table&gt;&#xA;  &lt;thead&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;th style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;Gotcha&lt;/th&gt;&#xA;          &lt;th style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;Explanation&lt;/th&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/thead&gt;&#xA;  &lt;tbody&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;Lots of different names for things&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;Fortinet have a wide range of products that do wildly different things. As an incident responder, it&amp;rsquo;s worth learning what these are and how they differ. FortiGate (appliance), FortiWeb (WAF), FortiClient (VPN agent), etc.&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;On-disk logging&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;Default is set to 7 days for devices with a disk. This can be increased to a maximum of 10 years (disk size pending). Persistent for appliances with a disk, non-persistent and wiped on reboot for a memory only appliance.&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;On-disk vs FortiAnalyzer&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;It is considered best-practice to additionally purchase a FortiAnalyzer and forward FortiGate appliance logs to this. This assists with retention, redundancy and advanced searching capabilities.&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;FortiOS is restricted&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;Does not offer a full shell capability for responders, only limited commands.&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;TAC report&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;A TAC report and debug logs can be retrieved via cli or GUI, providing output that may help investigate some attack scenarios.&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;fnsysctl&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;Some more advanced cli functionality is offered with fnsysctl commands; these are still restricted.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://community.fortinet.com/t5/FortiGate/Technical-Tip-Use-Cases-of-fnsysctl-Commands-for-System-Level/ta-p/391269&#34;&gt;https://community.fortinet.com/t5/FortiGate/Technical-Tip-Use-Cases-of-fnsysctl-Commands-for-System-Level/ta-p/391269&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;No easy access to underlying Linux OS&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;FortiGate uses a customized Linux kernel. Exploiting an RCE vulnerability (targeting a root-level process like &lt;code&gt;sslvpnd&lt;/code&gt; exploited in CVE-2022-49475) immediately grants an attacker root access to the host OS, allowing for persistent malware installation outside the view of standard FortiOS monitoring.&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;SSL-VPN is (should be) dead. Long live ZTNA&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;As of v7.6.3, the recommendation is to migrate SSL-VPN to IPSec or Zero Trust Network Access (ZTNA). The SSL-VPN feature will still receive patches and maintenance but no new capabilities will be added. &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.fortinet.com/document/fortigate/7.6.0/ssl-vpn-to-ipsec-vpn-migration/126460&#34;&gt;https://docs.fortinet.com/document/fortigate/7.6.0/ssl-vpn-to-ipsec-vpn-migration/126460&lt;/a&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.fortinet.com/document/fortigate/7.2.5/ssl-vpn-to-ztna-migration-guide/813800/deployment-overview&#34;&gt;https://docs.fortinet.com/document/fortigate/7.2.5/ssl-vpn-to-ztna-migration-guide/813800/deployment-overview&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;Single factor brute-force of SSL-VPN&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td style=&#34;text-align: left&#34;&gt;A lot of cyber incidents begin with brute-forcing of single factor credentials to the SSL-VPN. This would typically appear as an attacker authenticating to the SSL-VPN range using a compromised account. It is worth reviewing your authentication settings.&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/tbody&gt;&#xA;&lt;/table&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;forti-what&#34;&gt;Forti-What?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The thing that initially cooked me the most when responding to my first incident involving a FortiGate was just how many different product offerings there were. Below is a brief table of some of the more important products. While I won&amp;rsquo;t be discussing sales or best-practice architecture, it&amp;rsquo;s important to define these terms first for readers who may be unfamiliar with the product line, like I was.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bumblebee</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/bumblebee/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 19:54:35 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/bumblebee/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TL;DR&lt;/strong&gt; I dive into an SEO poisoning campaign delivering the Bumblebee loader, analyse a trojanised MSI pretending to be NirSoft software, and explore DLL sideloading in depth — including a hands-on look at export forwarding with a malicious &lt;code&gt;version.dll&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://miro.medium.com/v2/resize:fit:1400/format:webp/1*sKQr1BU6LqF3Z5vHTwukQg.png&#34; alt=&#34;Crude diagram of the attack chain, partially generated by ChatGPT and fixed in Photopea&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Scrolling through X, I came across &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/1ZRR4H/status/1925113739688177797&#34;&gt;this post&lt;/a&gt; that mentioned SEO poisoning affecting various software vendors and delivering the Bumblebee loader. This was later reported on by multiple sources, including &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/bumblebee-malware-distributed-via-zenmap-winmrt-seo-poisoning/&#34;&gt;BleepingComputer&lt;/a&gt;. Curious, I wanted to begin unpacking how this attack chain worked to see what I could learn along the way, so I picked a site at random and began the journey. This isn&amp;rsquo;t a full teardown; a JoeSandbox link with full IOCs and config is halfway down. I mainly wanted to document some curiosities I found along the way.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fake CAPTCHA leads to Vidar Stealer</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/vidar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2025 18:59:25 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/vidar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s been an apparent resurgence of fake CAPTCHA style malware delivery in the recent months. This is a fairly clever way of having a user unknowingly executable malicious code. In this post, we&amp;rsquo;ll attempt to follow along with execution, all the way from fake CAPTCHA to execution of final payload. This post will attempt to focus on how to analyse and follow execution in the event that sandboxes, articles or any outside help are unavailable, although these will be referenced at times.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ASyncRAT [IR/Malware Analysis]</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/asyncrat/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 14:55:40 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/asyncrat/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;sandbox-surfing&#34;&gt;Sandbox Surfing&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I&amp;rsquo;ve done one of these, but I had some time and thought I&amp;rsquo;d do quick analysis of whatever random file I found on public submissions of any.run. The file I landed on is named &lt;code&gt;xx.jpg&lt;/code&gt; (really a .zip file). This didn&amp;rsquo;t appear to be the original file in this infection chain, so I needed to pivot in VT and find the execution parent. You can do this by clicking the &lt;code&gt;relations&lt;/code&gt; tab and investigating the listed files.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bitter [IR/Malware Analysis]</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/bitter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 18:24:57 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/bitter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;bitter-apt&#34;&gt;Bitter (APT)&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Saw a tweet with a &lt;code&gt;.chm&lt;/code&gt; file showing 0 detections on VT and decided to check it out. TL;DR - I learned that the malware does nothing additional that the tweet didn&amp;rsquo;t already show, but here&amp;rsquo;s how I manually looked at it anyway.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;File Name: &amp;ldquo;CamScanner 10-07-2024 10.40.chm&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;MD5: 16807cb880073b1c21009f7749c8fe7f&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;SHA-1: 2f4c75347aada1894e6b90d1162374ef3ce7bedf&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;SHA-256: 1dd50966db005e30f7a69b6d16dfe8b9810dba3cdbe43bebb136f8786d027ed1&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Note: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.virustotal.com/gui/file/1dd50966db005e30f7a69b6d16dfe8b9810dba3cdbe43bebb136f8786d027ed1/detection&#34;&gt;VT Detection Rate is now: 2/64&lt;/a&gt;. The file is also detected by &lt;a href=&#34;https://app.docguard.io/1dd50966db005e30f7a69b6d16dfe8b9810dba3cdbe43bebb136f8786d027ed1/d331da0f-3143-4611-841c-b6f5443f72c8/0/results/dashboard&#34;&gt;DocGuard&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/static/bitter/Untitled.png&#34; alt=&#34;VirusTotal as of 14 Jul, 2024&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strela Stealer [IR/Malware Analysis]</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/strelastealer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2024 23:10:37 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/strelastealer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;strela-stealer&#34;&gt;Strela Stealer&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I decided to grab a random malware sample from &lt;a href=&#34;http://any.run&#34;&gt;any.run&lt;/a&gt; and have a bit of a poke around. The file I chose from public submissions has the following details:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;MD5: 09a3293c8e85921340f2e75cf398b0a5&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;FileName: 2585747226036.zip&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Extracted FileName: 2585747226036.js&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This file showed as &lt;a href=&#34;https://app.any.run/tasks/fd24f96b-532b-422e-90b8-bdc4b4adfe14/#&#34;&gt;no threats detected in the sandbox&lt;/a&gt;. Despite it showing no malicious activity (note the .dll error message box below which may be a deception technique or a legitimate error), a quick look at the AnyRun process tree shows some interesting things; we’ll keep this in mind for our analysis. The .zip file not present in VirusTotal, however the extracted file is (as we will see shortly).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HTB - SpookyLicense [reversing]</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/spookylicense/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2023 22:31:26 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/spookylicense/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;SpookyLicense is an “easy” reverse engineering challenge offered by HackTheBox, with “easy” in quotes as this one took me a considerable amount of effort. I am fairly new to reversing challenges and reverse engineering in general, but that’s what these are all about—learning new things. This was just my experience and there may be—as they say—more than one way to crack an egg. With all that being said, this is how I managed to solve the challenge.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HTB - Pandora&#39;s Bane [forensics]</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/pandorasbane/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2023 18:23:44 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/pandorasbane/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This was the final Forensics category challenge in HackTheBox&amp;rsquo;s recent CTF, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hackthebox.com/blog/cyber-apocalypse-2023-news&#34;&gt;Cyber Apocalypse — The Cursed Mission&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;My notes won&amp;rsquo;t be super detailed here as I didn&amp;rsquo;t do a whole lot of documentation during the CTF, so this is more just snippets of methodologies applied.&#xA;This one felt like a speedrun compared to how much time I spent getting stuck on the final decryption of Interstellar C2 (which I could not do, btw).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
